FRANCISCO LÓPEZ-SANCHO

SENIOR DEVELOPER

Specialized in Java and Scala

Profile

Certified Java Software developer

Skills

Development Currently developing

backend using Scala

Testing

Architecture & design

Ample experience in Testing Driven Development and BDD

Experience in Development of Software OO and Functional Programming, Design Patterns in a SDLC environment

Technical Knowledge

Development	Virtualization	Miscelánea
Core Java	VMWare: Workstation	Selenium,Jmeter
Scala, Akka	VirtualBox	Hudson,Sonar
Spring, JPA, JSF	Databases	Maven, Artifactory
Junit, Mockito, ScalaTest	Oracle, MySql, MongoDB	Scripting (UNIX and Powershell)
SOA, Web Services	os	Apache Tomcat, Weblogic, Jetty
R, Matlab	UNIX (Linux , AIX, OSX)	VBA, Python, PHP
Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash	IT Ops	Joomla
Spark	Chef,Vagrant	
Js: Backbone,Angular,Knockout		
Ruby on Rails		
AWS: EC2,S3,Glacier,Elastic		
Transcoder,OpsWork		
Subversion, Git		

Experience

Java/Scala Software Engineer

12/2013-today

I currently develop multiple solutions to help legal music commerce all around the world. Processing Data, building APIs as REST Web Services are some of the projects developed, some others involve Machine Learning and some Data Analisis with R. Almost every single solution works in a High Performance environment, 24/7. There's been many small projects in the last year and some quite big. Concretely, we had one quite big that processes social interactions in order to find whether they had ilegal content. It was the most important project in 2014 and I did 90% of it, from end to end.

Develop is based on Java, Scala, Akka, Spring, JPA through Test Driven Development. This tools query SQL and NoSQL Databases, MongoDB to be exact

The core team is eight people. I'm in charge of introducing new technologies to the rest of the group and give support to two juniors

Tools used Eclipse, SqlDeveloper, Maven, Hudson, Command Line, Amazon Web Services

Java Software Developer Argonet Comunicaciones S.L.

02/2012-11/2013

Project was an internal web solution for the Ministry of Defence. Project is a Web application that allows CRUD of complex tasks and also of its single elements.

Develop is based on JSF2, Spring, JPA and SOAP web services through Test Driven Development. Responsible for implementing migration from a legacy technology to Java, frontend and backend. In a team of four deciding best practices around JSF2. In all area leading Testing Driven Development. Tools used Eclipse, SqlDeveloper, Maven, Hudson, Sonar.

Java Software Developer

09/2008-02/2012

SoftwareAG Spain

Project 1 - 11/2010-02/2012

It was a Web Application for savings banks to provide capital grant to associations in a national scope. Application will manage this process: capital solicitation, steps until acceptation and track of the process itself.

Developed in a BPM, ESB and WS oriented framework.

Responsible for implementing required features, frontend and backend.

Tools used Eclipse, VmWare, SqlDeveloper, Ant.

Project 2 - 09/2008-11/2010

It was a Web Application for savings banks in a national scope to manage personal loans and mortgages. Application will manage this process: loan or mortgages solicitation, steps until acceptation and track of the process itself.

Developed in a BPM, ESB and WS oriented framework.

Responsible for implementing required features, frontend and backend.

Tools used Eclipse, VmWare, SqlDeveloper, Ant.

Ruby Software Developer

06/2007-06/2008

Intec. New Technologies consulting

Project was a Web Application aimed to support Entrepreneurs in her bussiness development under "Plan Avanza 2007" of Spanish Government. Application was designed as a table game. Each step will develop skills mostly through a little bit of theory and some question.

Developed using MySql, Ruby on Rails and an Apache Server.

Responsible for implementing required features, frontend and backend.

Tools used TextMate, MySqlWorkbench.

Microsoft Office Trainer

2000-2007

Different companies

Training Microsoft Office to different clients as NATO or Airbus

Other Projects (after 9 to 5 job)

Ruby Software Developer

03/2013-08/2013

Intec Consultancy Solutions Ltd

Project is a Web application to manage videos that is aimed to be

Project is a Web application to manage videos that is aimed to be a platform to upload videos, similar to youtube.

Develop is based on Backbone, Coffescript and Ruby on Rails.. Integration with Facebook, Twitter and Amazon Web Services and Nimbb.

Responsible for implementing migration from a Knockout technology to Backbone in the frontend and refactoring Backend to reduce it to a nutshell composed of API REST Services.

Tools used VirtuaBox, Vim, AWS EC2, S3 and OpsWork.

Education

ORACLE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL

Java SE 6 Programmer UNED (2011-2014)

Philosophy

Coursera (Sep 2014 - currently)

Data Science Specialization

Languages

Spanish Native level

English

High Level, written and spoken